Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection
1989-1996
Greenway Council
NPKMC-221-081
1.67 linear feet
Marist College Archives and Special Collections
The Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection documents the development and growth of the Greenway Council. The collection consists of handouts and minutes of meetings and clippings gathered and collected by the Greenway Council. The meetings cover a variety of topics, from local environmental hearings to expansion of the Council, to protecting the Hudson Riverbanks, parks, and hiking trails. The clippings cover topics of environmental importance in and around the Hudson River Valley.
Acquisitions Information
Hudson River Valley Greenway Council donated the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection to the Marist College Library in 1999.
Restrictions to Access
There are no restrictions on this collection
Related Collections
Grim Collection
Hudson River Environmental Society Library
Hudson River Valley Commission Collection
On the River Collection
Saunders Papers
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Administrative History Collection
Scenic Hudson, Inc. Collection
Seymour Papers
Hudson Valley GREEN Collection
Historical Note
“Preserve, enhance and develop the world-renowned scenic, natural, historic, cultural and recreational resources of the Hudson River Valley. Emphasis appropriate economic development activities and remain consistent with the Tradition of municipal home rule.” So states the Hudson River Valley Greenway Mission. Founded and run by volunteers, the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council seeks to preserve and protect the area surrounding the historic Hudson River. Not only is the Council interested in protecting the environment, but also the commercial, agricultural, and tourism interests in the area. With thirteen counties working together, the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council created and maintains the Hudson River Valley Greenway Act of 1991. The Greenway Act created two organizations: The Hudson River Valley Greenway Communities Council and the Greenway Conservancy for the Hudson River Valley. Both groups work together with the state, local, and county governments to create the best living and working environment for the Hudson Valley. Currently, the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council’s programs include: assistance for local planning events for communities, development of the Hudson River Valley Greenway Trail system, participation in the Hudson Valley Tourism Development Council, as well as many others.
Collection Overview
The Hudson River Valley Greenway Council Collection consists of handouts from meetings, maps, correspondence, and clippings collected by the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council concerning local issues of environmental and economic concern.
Arrangement of the Collection
These records are organized into two series: 1.Meetings 2. Clippings
Detailed Description of the Collection
- Meetings, 1; 0.67 Linear Feet; Boxes: 1-2; Folders: 1-20
  Series contains handouts, minutes, and speeches taken place during Hudson River Valley Greenway Council meetings.
  Arrangement: Chronological
  - 09/22/1989 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 11/17/1989 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - 12/09/1989 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - 01/10/1990 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 07/10/1990 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 07/18/1990 (Folder Box 1, File 6)
  - 08/16/1990 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - 09/10/1990 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - 10/03/1990 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - 10/09/1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - 11/07/1990 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - 11/20/1990 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - 11/30/1990 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - 12/06/1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - 02/13/1991 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - 03/26/1991 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - 07/03/1991 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - 08/12/1992 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Greenway Map (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Misc. Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Clippings, 2; 1 Linear Feet; Boxes: 3.5; Folders: 21-59
  Series contains clippings on various environmental and economic concerns in the Hudson Valley collected by the Hudson River Valley Greenway Council.
  - 08/1989 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - 09/1989 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - 12/1989 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - 01/1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - 07/1990 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - 09/1990 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - 10/1990 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - 11/1990 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - 01/1991 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - 03/1991 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - 05/1991 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - 06/1991 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - 07/1991 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - 08/1991 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - 09/1991 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - 10/1991 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - 12/1991 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - 01/1992 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - 02/1992 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - 03/1992 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - 007/1993 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - 08/1993 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - 11/1993 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - 04/1994 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - 06/1994 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - 08/1994 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - 09/1994 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - 0/1994 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - 11/1994 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - 02/1995 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - 03/1995 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - 04/1995 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - 01/1996 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - 02/1996 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - 03/1996 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - 08/1996 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 09/1996 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - 10/1996 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - 11/1996 (Box 5, Folder 59)